

Profile

Data Analyst/help desk analyst/programmer with 3 plus years of experience looking to utilize skills I have learned over the past several years to help others become more productive, enhance user experiences, and provide value to the business and their partners. I am a motivated self-starter, actively working to improve my skills and open to learning new technologies. You can view some the projects I have worked on in the past on my online portfolio found at:

https://mr-bland.github.io/Portfolio-DB/

Contact

PHONE:

864 363 7021

EMAIL:

daniel.byrd2@charter.net

LINKED-IN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielbyrd-090004170/

LOCATION

Taylors, SC

Willing to work remote

Key Skills

Data Analyst Programmer Analyst Help Desk Analyst Web Designer

Daniel Byrd

Data Analyst, Programmer, Designer, Help Desk Analyst

Work Experience

Service Desk Analyst at Pomeroy

(January 2020 – October 2023)

- Assisted UMB Bank with many technical issues from programs/systems not responding or operating correctly, to account unlocks and password resets. Completed a combined total of 12,000+ calls on various systems and issues.
- Constructed a HTML helper website designed to help format incident descriptions with pre-configured work notes for the most common issues. Also programed to have a separate page that allows the storage of the previously created incident descriptions.

Computer Programmer Intern at Budget Ninjas LLC

(July 2018 – October 2019) (Business Closed)

Technologies: Visual Studio, SQL, SSRS, ASP.NET, C#, Telerik, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Azure Devops

 Completed a number of projects to enhance their website and created an SSRS report for operations.

For more details please visit:

https://mr-bland.github.io/Portfolio-DB/

Education

<u>IBM Data Analyst Certification:</u> Completed certification course discussing and applying various technologies and methods for Data Analytics (2024)

<u>Greenville Technical College</u>: Associates degree in Computer Science (spring 2019)

LinkedIn Learning: Completed a number of technical courses.

Bonds Career Center: Technical training from 2015 to 2017